<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Forest ecology lab on :deciduous_tree:</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content in Forest ecology lab on :deciduous_tree:</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2018-2021 Marie-Hélène Brice.</copyright><atom:link href="https://mhBrice.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Communications</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/talks/</guid><description>Talks Brice M.-H.. Comment les perturbations influencent-elles la réponse des forêts au changement climatique ?. Midis de la foresterie 11/2020. UQAT Abitibi-Témiscamingue, Qc. Brice M.-H.. Dynamique spatio-temporelle des forêts dans l’écotone boréal-tempéré en réponse aux changements globaux. Soutenance de thèse de doctorat 09/2020. Montréal, Qc. Brice M.-H., Legendre P., Fortin M. Contraintes et moteurs des changements dans les forêts du Québec.</description></item><item><title>Join our team!</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/join/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/join/</guid><description>If you are interested in field or data based research related to the impact of anthropogenic pressures on plant communities, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place!
Undergraduate student If you are interested in doing a field or laboratory internship with our team, please do not hesitate to contact me by email to learn more about current projects. In your email, describe what motivates you to do an internship with us and tell me about your interests in ecology!</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/publications/</guid><description>Articles Grondin P., Brice M.-H., Boulanger Y., Morneau C., Couillard P., Richard P., Chalumeau A., Poirier V. (2022). Ecological classification in forest ecosystem management: Links between current practice and future climate change in a Québec case study. In: Girona MM, Morin H, Gauthier S, Bergeron Y (eds) Boreal forests in the face of climate change - Sustainable management. Advances in Global Change Research. Springer-Nature.. Kirk D., Brice M.-H., Bradstreet M.</description></item><item><title>Research projects</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/projects/</guid><description>Recent projects As temperatures increase, optimal climatic niches of many species are predicted to move northward by hundreds of kilometers beyond their current limits, and thus we might expect geographic range shifts. However, many non-climatic factors might vary along these climatic gradients, such as human-induced disturbances, interspecific competition and soil characteristics, with the potential to stop, slow down or accelerate potential range shifts.
Much of my current research centers around understanding and disentangling the influence of these factors on forest community changes from 3 different points of view: (1) ß diversity and community composition, (2) community transition dynamics and (3) functional traits.</description></item><item><title>Research themes</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/research/</guid><description>Ecology in the Anthropocene For more than a century, human activities have largely disrupted the dynamic equilibrium of natural cycles. Humans have transformed more than 50% of the earth&amp;rsquo;s surfaces, consume about 40% of the planet&amp;rsquo;s primary productivity each year and emit so many greenhouse gases that they have altered the global climate. These global changes transform biodiversity through feedback across the different levels of organization, from the individual organisms to populations, communities, ecosystems and biomes.</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/teaching/</guid><description>Courses 2013–2014, 2019-2020 Plant ecology course – BIO3753
Teaching assistant. Sampling methods in plant ecology and statistical analysis of plant community data.
Université de Montréal 2016–2019 Forest ecology course – BIO2703
Teaching assistant. Organized excursions in different regions of southern Quebec. Identification of tree species and ecology of forest communities.
Université de Montréal 2015–2017 Biostatistics 2 – BIO2042
Teaching assistant. Advanced methods of analysis of univariate and multivariate biological data.</description></item><item><title>Team members</title><link>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mhBrice.github.io/en/team/</guid><description>Marie-Hélène Brice Chercheuse principale, Je suis chercheuse-botaniste au Jardin Botanique de Montréal, professeure associée à l&amp;#39;Université de Montréal et membre de l&amp;#39;Institut de recherche en biologie végétale. En dehors du travail, je continue de regarder les plantes et de me promener en forêt! Samuel Martin MSc, 2022-... Comparaison de mélanges d&amp;#39;ensemencement pour le verdissement des fosses de plantation urbaines: identifier la meilleure solution en termes de la réduction des îlots de chaleur, de biodiversité et de niveau d’entretien.</description></item></channel></rss>